there have been some haunting new
developments with the brain organoids
the tiny human brains that we can grow
from stem cells and make to run a
computer what you see behind me are the
brain organoids working in real time
this was from the company that put them
on computer chips that is 16 human brain
organoids to a chip and sold them as a
subscription yes you can pay an
exorbitant price to use them and have
them do your computation but is the name
final spark not just haunting all on its
own one of the things that I had not
considered is that
they will develop around the task you
tell them to do and they'll get better
at it over time because they are living
their neurons work just like yours
because they are human neurons final
spark their idea is that these use like
a thousand times less energy than a
standard computer chip they are better
at doing some things like learning to
play Pong for example because we have
immersed them in what seems to be the
literal Matrix but they're going to get
better at the task at hand
and you can watch them do that you can
watch their brain waves in real time as
they do it one of the things that really
worries me is that we don't know what
their capabilities are we don't know
what they can become as we grow them for
longer and more complex and as we put
them in robots